<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linear-Algebra on Elias Judin - Category Theory &amp; Monadic Algebra Research</title>
    <link>/tags/linear-algebra/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linear-Algebra on Elias Judin - Category Theory &amp; Monadic Algebra Research</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© 2024 by Elias Judin</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 13:56:03 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/linear-algebra/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Linear Algebraic Geometry Part II</title>
      <link>/blog/linear-algebraic-geometry-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 16:24:16 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/linear-algebraic-geometry-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Below is a follow‐up blog post that explores the geometric implications and interpretations of the equivalence established in the previous post. In this discussion we explain how the abstract affine adjunction framework “geometrizes” the algebra–semimodule equivalence and what this means in concrete, geometric terms. The intended audience is graduate students in mathematics with some familiarity with category theory and universal algebra.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;geometric-interpretations-of-the-affine-adjunction-in-linear-varieties&#34;&gt;Geometric Interpretations of the Affine Adjunction in Linear Varieties&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In our previous post we saw how a linear variety of universal algebras—where every algebra is generated by its unary operations—can be shown to be equivalent to the category of semimodules over the semiring&lt;br&gt;&#xA;[&#xA;S := \operatorname{End}_{\mathcal{V}}(F(1))&#xA;]&#xA;of unary operations. This equivalence was obtained by specializing Olivia Caramello’s general affine adjunction framework to the linear case. In this follow‐up post we explore the geometric side of this equivalence. In particular, we discuss how the abstract operators and adjunctions, when interpreted geometrically, provide insight into the “coordinate geometry” underlying these algebras and how this perspective relates to familiar notions in algebraic geometry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linear Algebraic Geometry Part I</title>
      <link>/blog/linear-algebraic-geometry-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 16:20:50 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/linear-algebraic-geometry-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Below is a revised technical blog post written in flowing, well‐structured paragraphs. The post explains how your work on linear varieties of universal algebras and their equivalence to the category of semimodules over the semiring of unary operations fits naturally into Olivia Caramello’s general affine adjunction framework. The exposition is aimed at graduate students in mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;bridging-linear-varieties-and-semimodules-via-general-affine-adjunctions&#34;&gt;Bridging Linear Varieties and Semimodules via General Affine Adjunctions&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In recent years, abstract dualities and adjunctions have become powerful tools in many areas of mathematics. One particularly influential development is the general affine adjunction framework developed by Caramello, Marra, and Spada, which abstracts the classical correspondence between affine algebraic varieties and coordinate rings into a categorical setting. In my work on linear varieties of universal algebras, I establish an equivalence between such a variety and the category of semimodules over the semiring of unary operations. In this post, we explain how this concrete equivalence fits into Caramello’s general framework, detailing each step and verifying all calculations along the way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
